Next is the most important part, the part of making the skirt itself.
When making the skirt itself, we need to draw a skirt that is wider and longer than the inner skirt.
After creating the board, because we just created the board by overlapping,
now put the board separately in the 2D window, press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical board.
After creating the board, we select the board in the 3D space and rotate it to the side of the virtual model.
Why don't we use the frame here?
Because if we use the frame, because this board is still too long,
even if we set the frame to the maximum, it will still have some contrast with the model.
In fact, in this case, we can just put the whole board on the side of the virtual model.
When we switch the picture to the physical surface,
we can see that the model is in the 3D space.
Remember to make sure that your skirt is facing the outside.
Put it to the side is also to make the board and belt merge together,
so that there is no problem that the board will pass through the whole body to sew.
After that, we will use the line sewing tool to merge the top of the board and the belt together.
Then create the sewing line between the front and the back of the button.
Then, after opening the simulation by pressing the control key,
we wait for the skirt to be worn.
After wearing the skirt,
it is a regular operation to reduce the粒子間距 and reduce the conflict thickness.
After we have reduced the粒子間距,
because of the increase in the number of faces of the grid,
the overall simulation speed will be slower,
so it is very useful for us to freeze other unrelated boards in the early stages.
When opening the simulation, we can manually drag the board,
so that its wrinkles are more evenly distributed.
In addition,
we can narrow the whole board a little bit to reduce the wrinkles on the waist.
When choosing the middle board,
the dual center can activate the center point.
After activating the center point,
whether it is the size of the adjustment board or the rotation board,
it is based on the center point.
Therefore, its board modification will not be biased towards the side of our adjustment,
but the front and back adjustment at the same time.
At present, the fabric we are using for the women's pool group looks very good overall.
The body looks very soft.
So we choose the fabric of the previous skirt version,
directly copy the same fabric,
drag this piece of fabric on the newly created women's pool group,
and then we increase the bending strength of this piece of fabric a little bit.
After opening the simulation,
we will see that this skirt is slightly open,
it has a certain support,
it will not stick to the skin like before.
When modifying these properties,
remember that the number of diagonal lines is often smaller than the direction of the gold sand and the tail sand.
When modifying these properties, remember that the number of diagonal lines is often smaller than the direction of the gold sand and the tail sand.
After the adjustment is done,
we select the outer layer of the board.
Press the Shift key to click to select more.
After selecting,
press Shift Q to hide,
and then we activate the frozen board inside.
Let's simulate.
Press Shift W to display all the clothing boards.
At this time, let's simulate.
After the simulation is stable,
we will start to reduce the rate of the inner layer board from 40 to 100 gradually.
Note that when you shrink it,
you must shrink it little by little,
do not shrink it too much at a time.
Otherwise, it may cause the board to slip and slip,
causing the board to slip and be unstable.
Select the outer layer board.
Press Shift Q to hide them.
We can see that the inner layer board is actually more compressed,
because there are more outer layers.
At this time,
we put the inner layer board,
and after its bending strength is increased,
we will see that it will gradually stretch the outer board.
At this time, after displaying all the boards,
we will see that
because we have modified the bending strength of the inner layer board,
in fact, the outer board,
these wrinkles are still retained.
It's just that it looks like it's been stretched a little bit.
In order to have a more detailed wrinkle effect,
I reduced the particle diameter here to 8,
and then simulated it again.
Press Shift Q to hide the inner layer board.
If we want to make this skirt look softer,
we can reduce its fine-tuning strength
and the strength of the corner line a little bit.
After this attribute is reduced,
the straightness of the entire board will be more obvious.
However, in the position of the seam,
because the inner layer board has a bending strength to support it,
plus its own bending strength,
it will not be very close.
The more obvious difference is that it is in the area of ​​the lower part,
not the area of ​​the seam.
The bending strength is more obvious in the area of ​​the seam.
Then we have to activate the belt.
Let's simulate it together and apply these modifications.
Then we activate all the boards and simulate them together.
Of course, in my video,
I made the top and skirt separately.
You can also sew the top directly to the belt.
Then the skirt is sewn on the belt to make a whole.
Then we start to optimize the details.
First of all, select the flower edge of the middle part.
Here we reduce the particle diameter of the flower edge a little bit.
When the particle diameter is 5,
its fold will be more delicate and the transition will be smoother.
The reason why we did not modify it so low in the early stage
is that the particle diameter will also affect our simulation speed when it is relatively small.
Even if you freeze, it will still affect it to a certain extent.
In addition,
we can apply the same fabric to the shoulder of this board.
After selecting the previous board,
click on the small arrow next to the fabric.
You can also apply this fabric to the selected board.
First, we need to use a tool called pressure.
After selecting the board,
in the model editor,
if we apply the negative pressure to the board,
then the board will definitely receive a force from its front to its back,
and the board will be pressed against the virtual model.
If you think that the negative pressure of this model
is still a little big,
we can click on the small arrow on the left side of the pressure.
In the purple menu below,
enter the value of the number with a small point,
such as negative 0.5,
so that we can ensure that the fabric and this pressure have a certain balance.
On the contrary,
if we apply a positive pressure to the board,
then it will receive a fixed force from the back to the board,
and the board will be stretched.
Because the board and other boards have the effect of fission lines,
it will not be blown away.
For example,
if you directly apply pressure to the board on the outermost layer,
it looks a little unreal.
Then we can apply pressure to the inner layer of the skirt.
For the skirt,
if you feel that the pressure is not enough when the value is 1,
then we can continue to increase its pressure value.
The higher the pressure value,
the greater the horizontal force applied to this board.
Then the effect of its support will be more obvious.
Because the direction of pressure is from the back to the front,
and the direction of the bending force is the board itself,
it is not easy to bend.
So the bending force is relatively obvious,
it will arch in the seam area.
Because there is a lot of fabric piled up in the seam area.
But what about the pressure?
Because the seam area has its own force,
so it is not so easy to blow up.
But the bottom plate,
it has no other force,
only the fabric itself is relatively easy to blow up.
Everyone needs to adjust the pressure of the inner board.
If we already have a skirt on the outside,
and we want to modify the skirt length of the inner skirt,
there will be a gap in the middle.
Then we first reactivate the outer board,
so that it does not affect the inner board simulation.
For the inner board,
we will cancel its pressure first,
make it a more close state,
and then find a way to cover the outer board outside.
First of all, we continue to modify it,
modify its length to the appropriate length.
Here I will mention that,
we do not use layers directly,
because the skirt has a lot of pleating.
The pleating area itself has a lot of mesh puncture.
If you add layers to calculate,
it will not be stable.
Then repeat the previous operation,
reduce the tail shrink rate of the inner board to 60 or 40,
and simulate the outer board of the skirt.
After the simulation is stable,
return the shrink rate of the inner board to 100 little by little.
Note that when we return,
we must return little by little.
If there is a very unstable place like the picture,
then we will press Ctrl Z to return to the previous step.
Then this time,
do not add such a big number.
Before we were 80 directly to 100,
now we are 80 to 90,
90 to 100 again.
Now it's basically stable.
If you still have a little unstable when you simulate,
then you go from 90 to 95,
and then to 100.
Now the inner and outer boards have been simulated and stabilized,
then we will add the pressure of the inner board back.
Then press Ctrl key to start the simulation,
wait for the board to be simulated.
Rotate the view,
look at the overall simulation effect.
If you think that the current women's clothing is too obvious,
we can appropriately reduce its pressure a little more.
Click on the triangle next to the pressure,
you can enter the specific value.
If the inner layer is relatively long,
we can slightly shorten the inner layer.
And in the 2D window,
the board and the board must not overlap.
This will affect the UV image we pour out.
Then use the edit board tool
to drag the bottom board of the skirt up.
You can shorten the skirt.
Because the shortened board,
it just removes part of the board,
so it will not have a conflict with the outer board.
Then we simulate it.
Then we switch to the rectangle tool,
draw a cross-sectional board
that is a little wider than the women's clothing.
Then we use the line powder tool
to create a line between the two boards.
After that,
switch to the adjustment board tool,
select the board,
Ctrl D,
create a symmetrical board,
and then select the right-click menu,
add to the side.
If there is a board that turns to the inside of the skirt,
then we will choose to add to the side again.
Adding to the side
This function will automatically arrange the lines between it and another board along the board
on the side of other boards.
Then we open the simulation,
the edge of the board is done.
If you don't think it has enough wrinkles,
we can widen the edge of the board a little more.
But after we widen it,
you will see that
because we just widened it in the direction of the back center,
if we directly open the simulation,
the board will be a little unstable.
So after we adjust it,
we can select the middle board,
right-click,
select again,
add to the side.
It is the same as its symmetrical board,
select the middle board,
right-click,
select to add to the side.
Then we simulate again.
After the simulation is done,
we press N,
switch to the line powder tool,
close the front center,
and then close the back center.
I don't know if you have found that
although the width is different
between the horizontal edge and the women's skirt,
but in the position of the horizontal edge,
they can be connected,
and there is no obvious wrinkle.
That's because
our skirt part,
its fabric itself,
the stretching performance is better,
and it is easier to stretch.
Therefore, the horizontal edge
will make the bottom of the symmetrical skirt
a little wider,
and the wrinkle will not be obvious.
If we use the editing board tool
to select the bottom line of the women's skirt,
open its elasticity,
and set the elasticity ratio to 100,
then this line
will apply a elasticity.
This elasticity
makes this line
maintain its original length.
It will not be affected by the horizontal edge,
so that the wrinkles
are evenly distributed
between the two panels,
but let the wrinkles
all reflect on the horizontal edge.
In this way,
its wrinkles will be more obvious.
In fact,
for the current application of
the elasticity ratio of 100,
it can not only be used
on the flower edge,
but it can also be used
on any part of the skirt.
You do not want to
stretch the deformation
due to the seam of the fabric,
or due to the gravity of the fabric,
the position of the stretch deformation
will be affected.
For example,
like the neckline
I showed in the video.